BABAK GHOLAMPOUR

Senior Android Developer

Tehran, Iran, C: +989127616539 | b.gholampour@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Website

CAREER OVERVIEW

Software developer with over 7 years' experience, especially in designing, developing and testing Android Applications. Experienced in creating readable and easily maintainable source code. Also highly motivated in learning new technologies and work in a team to achieve teamwork advantages.

My recent experience involved designing and implementing solutions for integrating blockchain and web3.0 technologies into Android devices.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Mobile application development and design
- Experienced in Object Oriented Programming
- Experienced in Software design
- Experienced in AndroidX libraries like WorkManager and Livedata
- Experienced in working with 3rd party libraries like Retrofit, Glide, Kotlin Coroutines, Hilt(dependency injection) and etc
- Experienced in Rational Databases
- Strong understanding of Blockchain and Web3.0 technologies, including Smart Contracts, Solidity, EVM networks, and public/private keys.
- Experienced in work with tools like GIT and Mercurial as VCS
- Ability to learn new technologies quickly and independently
- Complex problem-solving
 - Fluent in English

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Skills	Proficiency	Total Years	Last Used
Android Platform	Expert	7	Recently
Java	Proficient	6	Recently
Kotlin	Proficient	4	Recently
Blockchain and Web3 knowledge	Beginner	1	Recently

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2021 to present Lead Android Developer

Naika DAO - Remote

DAO (Decentralized Autonomous Organization) is an emerging form of legal structure that has no central governing body and whose members share a common goal to act in the best interest of the entity. Naika DAO's goal is to bring Web3.0 to mobile. Naika ecosystem consists of 3 main products: Naika OS, Naika dApp Store and Naika Pay.

https://naika.io

- Design and development of <u>Naika Pay library</u>. Naika Pay is an Android library which enables dApp (decentralized Android Application) developers to integrate payment with cryptocurrencies in their products.
- Design and development of <u>Naika dApp Store</u>, an Android application that hosts dApps and allows
 users to install/uninstall dApps on their Android devices.

- Experience working with different Blockchain/Web3.0 protocols and technologies like Web3j,
 Wallet Connect and Ethereum smart contracts.
- Participation in technical and planning meetings with other teams.

02/2020 to 02/2021 Lead Android Developer

CodeFeld - Tehran, Iran

Work on international mobile applications. CodeFeld is a German/Iranian company that its focus is providing end-to-end mobile app development services.

- Design and implementation of a chat module using Socket.io.
- Contribute on application's system architecture and API design.
- Design and implementation of SQLite databases using Room.
- Implementing Hilt and Kotlin Koin as dependency injection frameworks.
- Ensure codes that written by team is clear, clean and efficient.
- LeakCanary library was used for tracking of memory leaks.

02/2019 to 02/2020 Senior Android Developer

Alopeyk On-demand delivery - Tehran, Iran

Work on Alopeyk's native mobile applications, AloPeyk is the leading on-demand urban logistics platform with about 4 million active users in Iran, bringing instant delivery within anyone's reach. It uses an extensive network of motorcycle couriers to form a logistics network that's fast, cheap and reliable.

https://alopeyk.com

- Choosing MVVM as a suitable deign pattern for the project.
- Write fully modular components for the project.
- Choosing Kotlin as primary programming language.
- Using Kotlin Coroutines for asynchronous programming.
- Using Android Architecture Components for write robust, testable and maintainable codes.
- Writing unit test with over 60 percent code coverage.

11/2017 to 02/2019 Senior Android Developer

Bisphone Telecom - Tehran, Iran

Work on BisphonePlus project, BisPhone is a communication app for smart phones. It's easy to use and optimized and convenient for everyday use. BisPhone recommended the easiest way for sending various type of messages such as text messages, media messages, location, file and etc.

- Contribute and design many new feature specifications.
- Ensure codes that written by team is clear, clean and efficient.
- Implementing End to End Encryption Secret Chat with Diffie-Hellman key exchange and AES encryption.
- Implementing resumable file and media download/upload.

01/2016 to 11/2017 Android Developer

Bisphone Telecom - Tehran, Iran

- Implementing app2app and app2out call over VOIP in BisphonePlus with PJSIP (SIP implementation on NDK).

- Design and implement many RPCs with server using protocol buffers (Google's data interchange format)
- Develop the database wrapper functions for data staging and modeled the data objects relevant to the mobile application.
- Implementing gallery and media manipulation in project.
- Implementing custom view components and UI.

08/2015 to 01/2016 Android Developer

TANA Co - Tehran, Iran

TANA is a multi-service company known as CallWithMe in Internet and

Internet Telephony industry.

htttp://callwithme.com

- Implementing Android applications that communicate with RESTful services.

ACTIVITIES AND HONORS

- Head manager of scientific associations in Shahrood University of Technology 2011 2012
- Manager of IT scientific association in Shahrood university of Technology 2010 2011
- Organizer of 1st ACM contest in the east area in shahrood university of Technology 2011

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2017 Master of Science: Software Design and Development

Shiraz University – Tehran

2013 Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Shahrood University of Technology – Shahrood, Semnan